Charles Wharton Stork Papers
Charles Wharton Stork Papers
- Writings (1993 accession)
  - Misc. poems (Box 20)
  - The White Top Festival, manuscript story (Box 20)
  - Falstaff on Broadway – one act play, last page is manuscript (Box 20)
  - The Shudder in "Don Giovanni", translation (Box 20)
  - Letter, unknown author or recipient (Box 20)
  - Misc. fragments (Box 20)
  - Several poems on Burlington Hotel (London) note paper, manuscript (Box 20)
    Rapture Song
    Song City
    I Live Two Lives
    The Reconciliation
    The Buccaneer of Beauty
    I Do Not Sail Alone
    To a Laughter Sprite
  - Misc. poems (Box 20)
  - Misc. poems (Box 20)
  - Have Faith, America, musical score; words by CWS, music by G.F. Stork (Box 20)
  - Misc. poems and fragments (Box 20)
  - John Hall Wheelock, American Poet, essay (Box 20)
  - Several short stories or essays by CWS
    - Personal Impressions of Bernard Shaw (Box 20)
    - Gustaf Fröding – Sweden's Greatest Lyric Poet (Box 20)
    - With a Mouth Organ (Box 20)
    - A Petal on a Lonely Path (Box 20)
    - The Baffled Grouch (Box 20)
  - Poems, possibly by Stephen Boylan Bird (Box 20)
  - Misc. poems (some in Swedish/Scandinavian) (Box 20)
  - Terpsichores Lund (in Swedish) (Box 20)
  - Calantha – A Dramatic Idyll (Box 20)
  - Three Episodes in the Life of Ninon, novel (Box 20)
  - Lighthouse Ledge, novel (Box 20)
  - Misc. poems, fragments and translations (Box 20)
  - Music scores
    - Tercentenary Hymn (Box 20)
    - Hark, Hark the Lark (Box 20)
    - Let There be Light (Box 20)
    - My Father (Box 20)
    - Two Songs: Tempting Waves, Lullaby (Box 20)
    - United We Stand (Box 20)
    - Prelude (Box 20)
    - The Twenty-Third Psalm (Box 20)
    - Father's Beauty (Box 20)
    - Victory March (Box 20)
    - The Soul of the Universe (Box 20)
    - College Days (?) (Box 20)
  - Poems by CWS
    - The Pianist as Mystic (Box 21)
    - A Painter's Christ (Box 21)
    - Grass Roots (Box 21)
    - The Sentries – a True Incident of the War (Box 21)
    - The Mystic in the Grand Stand (Box 21)
    - For Cynthia (Box 21)
    - The Ballad of Mir Magbool Sherwani, A Modern Kashmiri Ballad (Box 21)
  - Several short poems by CWS (Box 21)
  - Man Brutes (Box 21)
  - Short poems (Box 21)
  - Poems by CWS (Box 21)
    - The Dance is Unity (Box 21)
    - A Tribute to Walt (Box 21)
    - Of Cats and Dogs (Box 21)
    - A Treasure Box (Box 21)
    - The Triumph of Love (Box 21)
    - For a National Poetry Day (Box 21)
    - The Touchstone (Box 21)
  - Several short poems by CWS (Box 21)
  - Poems by CWS
    - Apologia (Box 21)
    - Portrait of a Centenarian (Box 21)
  - Several short poems by CWS (Box 21)
  - The Head of McClain, poem (Box 21)
  - Toby, long poem (Box 21)
  - Erasmus, poem (Box 21)
  - Small address and notebook (Box 21)
  - Poems by CWS
    - A Rose Confesses (Box 21)
    - To Stones from a New England Beach (Box 21)
    - Thought and Negation (Box 21)
  - Out of the Dark – a Three-Act play (Box 21)
  - Several short poems by CWS (Box 21)
  - Tagore's International College, short story (Box 21)
  - Several short poems by CWS (Box 21)
  - What is Originality: An Adventure in Criticism, essay (Box 21)
  - Poems translated from Swedish by CWS
    - Since I'm Born (Box 21)
    - Song to Salome (Box 21)
    - The Cachuca (Box 21)
    - The Night Wind (Box 21)
    - piece from 'Moonlight Night' (Box 21)
    - The Triumph of Love, poem (Box 21)
  - Poems translated from Swedish by CWS
    - Rest We Beside the Spring Here (Box 21)
    - Yes, You are Heavy, but my Love is Strong (Box 21)
    - The Nixie to the Girl (Box 21)
    - The Laboring Brother (Box 21)
    - Brother and Sister (Box 21)
    - To the Night Wind (Box 21)
    - Nameless and Immortal (Box 21)
  - Several short poems by CWS (Box 21)
  - Short biography of Frances Barton Gummere (Box 21)
  - Poems and contents page by CWS (Box 21)
  - Short poems (Box 21)
  - The Tales of Ensign Stal, book of poems translated from Swedish by CWS (Box 21)
  - Ninon, play in two acts (Box 21)
  - The Egoist, comedy in four acts (Box 21)
  - Falstaff on Broadway, play (Box 21)
  - Shy Adventurer, novel (Box 21)
  - Ode to Sanity (Box 21)
  - The King of Thule (Box 21)
  - The Ballad of Maqbool Sherwani (Box 21)
  - Muckle-Mouthed Meg, a Parable on an Old Story (Box 21)
  - Flying Fish: An Ode, poem (Box 21)
  - London, poem (Box 21)
  - For Americans Mainly, a Moving Picture with Reflections by CWS (Box 21)
  - Memories of England, poems (Box 21)
  - Several short poems by CWS (Box 21)
  - A Changeling Transformed: A Review of 'The People of Japan' by Pearl Buck, review
  - Several short poems by CWS (Box 21)
  - Poems and reviews by CWS (Box 21)
  - Poems and reviews by CWS (Box 21)
  - Several short poems by CWS (Box 21)
  - Several short poems by CWS (Box 21)
  - A Hint from the Birds (Box 21)
  - The Nails (Box 21)
  - The Man in Front of Me (Box 21)
- Photographs (1993 accession)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22)
- Writings (1993 accession)
  - Shy Adventurer, typescript autobiographical novel; 2 copies (Box 23)
  - The Vineyard and the Sea, published book (Box 23)
  - Glimpses of Our Von Pausinger Heritage, published book (Box 23)
  - Misc. writings (Box 23)
  - Books by Lisl Stork (Box 23)
  - Misc. writings (Box 23a)
- Correspondence (1993 accession)
  - Family (Box 24-26)
  - Miscellaneous, unidentified (Box 27)
- Correspondence-subject files (1993 accession)
  - A (Box 28)
  - Ackerman, Barbara (Box 28)
  - Albertson, Charles C. (Box 28)
  - Aldington, Hilda (Box 28)
  - Aldis, Dorothy (Box 28)
  - Aldis, Mary (Box 28)
  - Allen, Frederick Lewis (Box 28)
  - Allen, Hervey (Box 28)
  - Allinson, Francis G. (Box 28)
  - Allwood, Martin Samuel (Box 28)
  - American Scandinavian Foundation (Box 28)
  - Atherton, Percy Lee (Box 28)
  - The Atlantic Monthly (Box 28)
  - Aughiltree, Ruth (Box 28)
  - Auslander, Joseph (Box 28)
  - Austin, Mary Hunter (Box 28)
  - Avery, Claribel Weeks (Box 28)
  - B, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Bacon, Leonard (Box 28)
  - Bates, Katharine Lee (Box 28)
  - Beebe, William (Box 28)
  - Bell, Ralcy Husted (Box 28)
  - Bellows, Henry Adams (Box 28)
  - Benet, Stephen Vincent (Box 28)
  - Benet, William Rose (Box 28)
  - Benson, Adolph B. (Box 28)
  - Betts, Anna Whelan (Box 28)
  - Bickham, Martin Hays (Box 28)
  - Biddle, Katherine, See Chapin, Katherine Garrison (Box 28)
  - Bimboni, Alberto (Box 28)
  - Bird, Robert Lee, See Bird, Stephen Moylan (Box 28)
  - Bird, Stephen Moylan (Box 28)
  - Bispham, David Scull (Box 28)
  - Black, MacKnight (Box 28)
  - Blyth, Edward (Box 28)
  - Bodenheim, Maxwell (Box 28)
  - The Bookman (Box 28)
  - Bradford, Gamaliel (Box 28)
  - Braithwaite, William Stanley (Box 28)
  - Briggs, LeBaron Russell (Box 28)
  - Brinton, Christian (Box 28)
  - Brooke, Tucker (Box 28)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck (Box 28)
  - Brown, Abbie Farwell (Box 28)
  - Bryce, James Bryce (Box 28)
  - Buchanan, Annabel Morris (Box 28)
  - Buck, Pearl S. (Box 28)
  - Burt, Maxwell Struthers (Box 28)
  - Bynner, Wtter (Box 28)
  - C (2 folders) (Box 29)
  - Carpenter, Edward Childs (Box 29)
  - Carpenter, Rhys (Box 29)
  - Carroll, Ellen M. (Box 29)
  - Carver, Gertrude Nason (Box 29)
  - Champness, Patricia (Box 29)
  - Chapin, Katherine Garrison (Box 29)
  - Coates, Florence Earle (Box 29)
  - Coatsworth, Elizabeth Jane (Box 29)
  - Coblentz, Stanton Arthur (Box 29)
  - Comfort, William Wister (Box 29)
  - Conkling, Grace Hazard (Box 29)
  - Cook, Amory Hare (Box 29)
  - Cunningham, Nora B. (Box 29)
  - D (Box 29)
  - Daingerfield, Elliott (Box 29)
  - Dale, Virginia (Box 29)
  - Dalton, Power (Box 29)
  - Dana, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow (Box 29)
  - Dargan, Olive Tilford (Box 29)
  - Davidson, Gustav, See Poetry Society of America
  - Davies, Mary Carolyn (Box 29)
  - Dell, Floyd, See The Masses
  - The Dial (Box 29)
  - Dole, Nathan Haskell (Box 29)
  - Douglas, Hugh A. (Box 29)
  - Draper, John W. (Box 29)
  - Dresbach, Glenn Ward (Box 29)
  - Driscoll, Louise (Box 29)
  - DuPont, Marcella Miller (Box 29)
  - E (Box 30)
  - Eastman, Max (Box 30)
  - Eliot, Ethel Cook (Box 30)
  - Eliot, Samuel Atkins (Box 30)
  - England, George Allan (Box 30)
  - Erskine, John (Box 30)
  - Everybody's Magazine (Box 30)
  - Ewing, Amy (Box 30)
  - F (Box 30)
  - Farrar, John (Box 30)
  - Ferargil (Box 30)
  - Ficke, Arthur Davison (Box 30)
  - Fitzmaurice-Kelly, James (Box 30)
  - The Forum (Box 30)
  - Foster, Ethel (Box 30)
  - Fox, Mary Lindley (Box 30)
  - Francke, Kuno (Box 30)
  - Frederick, John T. (Box 30)
  - Samuel French, Inc. (Box 30)
  - Frothingham, Robert (Box 30)
  - G (Box 30)
  - Galahad, Joseph Andrew (Box 30)
  - Galsworthy, John (Box 30)
  - Garber, Daniel (Box 30)
  - Garnett, Louise Ayers (Box 30)
  - Gessier, Clifford (Box 30)
  - Gest, John Marshall (Box 30)
  - Ginsberg, Louis (Box 30)
  - Glasgow, Ellen (Box 30)
  - Goodwin, Henry Buergel (Box 30)
  - Grant, Percy Stickney (Box 30)
  - Gray, Agnes Kendrick (Box 30)
  - Griffith, Beatrice Fox (Box 30)
  - Guiterman, Arthur (Box 30)
  - Gummere, Francis Barton (Box 30)
  - Gummere, Richard M. (Box 30)
  - Hagedorn, Hermann (Box 31)
  - Haley, Molly Anderson (Box 31)
  - Hall, Amanda Benjamin, 1918-1950; undated; 10 folders (Box 31)
  - Hall, Hazel (Box 32)
  - Hallowell, Harriet Hall (Box 32)
  - Hambro, Carl Joachim (Box 32)
  - Hammond, Eleanor (Box 32)
  - Hancock, Walker (Box 32)
  - Hanes, Leigh (Box 32)
  - Haverford College (Box 32)
  - Hearst, James (Box 32)
  - Hergesheimer, Joseph (Box 32)
  - Heyward, DuBose (Box 32)
  - Hird, Frank (Box 32)
  - Hoffman, Phoebe (Box 32)
  - Hoge, Dorothy Anderson (Box 32)
  - Hoisington, May Folwell (Box 32)
  - Holme, Jamie Sexton (Box 32)
  - Huckfield, Leyland (Box 32)
  - I (Box 32)
  - Inman, Arthur (Box 32)
  - J (Box 32)
  - Jackinson, Alex (agent) (Box 32)
  - Jenkins, Charles Francis (Box 32)
  - Jennings, Leslie Nelson (Box 32)
  - Johnson, Edith Warner (Box 32)
  - Johnson, Ida Judith (Box 32)
  - Johnson, Josephine (Box 32)
  - Johnson, Julia Davis (Box 32)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood (Box 32)
  - K (Box 32)
  - Keith, Joseph Joel (Box 32)
  - Kelly, Charles Arthur (Box 32)
  - Kendrick, Lucile (Box 32)
  - Kenyon, Bernice Lesbia (Box 32)
  - Kindler, Hans (Box 32)
  - King, Ethel (Box 32)
  - Kinsolving, Sally Bruce (Box 32)
  - Kittredge, George Lyman (Box 32)
  - Klapp, William H. (Box 32)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred (Box 32)
  - L (Box 32)
  - John Lane Company (Box 32)
  - Laramore, Vivian Yeiser (Box 32)
  - Laurin, Thorsten (Box 32)
  - Leach, Henry Goddard (Box 32)
  - Lee, Gerald Stanley (Box 32)
  - Leitch, Mary Sinton (Box 33)
  - Lewis, William Draper (Box 33)
  - Lindabury, Richard V. (Box 33)
  - Lindsay, Vachel (Box 33)
  - Livesay, Florence Randal (Box 33)
  - Long, Haniel (Box 33)
  - Long, John Luther (Box 33)
  - Longfellow, Herbert H. (Box 33)
  - Longstreth, Morris, See Longstreth, Thomas Morris
  - Longstreth, Thomas Morris, 1905-1968; undated; 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Longstreth, William (Box 33)
  - Lowell, Amy (Box 33)
  - Lowry, Robert (Box 33)
  - Lundbergh, Holger M., 2 folders (Box 33)
  - McCall, Virginia (Box 33)
  - McCarter, Henry (Box 33)
  - McCluskey, Katherine Wisner (Box 33)
  - McCoy, Samuel Duff (Box 33)
  - Edward MacDowell Memorial Association (Box 33)
  - McGee, Margaret B. (Box 33)
  - Mackaye, Percy (Box 33)
  - McKenzie, Ethel and Robert Tait (Box 33)
  - Maclagan, Eric Robert Dalrymple (Box 33)
  - MacLeish, Archibald (Box 33)
  - Macmillan Company (Box 33)
  - Mahler, Alma (Box 33)
  - Markham, Anna Catherine (Box 33)
  - Markham, Lucia Clark (Box 33)
  - Marks, Jeannette Augustus (Box 33)
  - Masefield, John (Box 33)
  - The Masses (Box 33)
  - Meigs, Margaret Wister, See Wister, Margaret
  - Mencken, H. L. (Box 33)
  - Middleton, Scudder (Box 33)
  - Mitchell Kennerley, Publisher (Box 33)
  - Montgomery, Roselle Mercier (Box 33)
  - Moreland, John Richard (Box 34)
  - Morley, Christopher (Box 34)
  - Morris, Harrison S. (Box 34)
  - Morris, Kenneth (Box 34)
  - Morton, David (Box 34)
  - Mowrer, Paul Scott (Box 34)
  - Mukerji, Dhan Gopal (Box 34)
  - Murphy, Charles R. (Box 34)
  - Myers, Albert Cook (Box 34)
  - N (Box 34)
  - The Nation (Box 34)
  - Nevin, Hardwick, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Newton, A. Edward (Box 34)
  - Nickerson, Paul Sumner, 1922-1958; undated; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Nimitz, Chester W. (Box 34)
  - Novak, Sonia Ruthele, 1918-1926, undated; 3 folders (Box 34)
  - Nutter, Medora Addison (Box 34)
  - O (Box 34)
  - Oakley, Thornton (Box 34)
  - O'Conor, Norreys Jephson (Box 34)
  - Olsen, Charles (Box 34)
  - Olson, Ted (Box 34)
  - O'Sheel, Shaemas (Box 34)
  - P, 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Page, Curtis Hidden (Box 35)
  - Page, Dorothy, 1921-1945; undated; 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Pageant Press (Box 35)
  - Palmer, George Herbert (Box 35)
  - Parrish, Maxfield (Box 35)
  - Patterson, Antoinette (Box 35)
  - Patterson, Marjorie (Box 35)
  - Peel, Robert P.E.N. (Box 35)
  - Penniman, Josiah Harmar (Box 35)
  - Percy, Wlliam Alexander (Box 35)
  - Pfeiffer, Edward H. (Box 35)
  - Phelps, William Lyon (Box 35)
  - Pinder, Frances Dickenson (Box 35)
  - Poetry (Box 35)
  - Poetry Society of America (Box 35)
  - Porcher, Mary F. Wckham (Box 35)
  - Post, Chandler Rathfon (Box 35)
  - Pound, Ezra (Box 35)
  - Price, Frederic Newlin, See Ferargil
  - R (Box 36)
  - Rains, Claude (Box 36)
  - Rathbone, Basil (Box 36)
  - Ravenel, Beatrice St. Julian (Box 36)
  - Reese, Lizette Woodworth (Box 36)
  - Ribbing, Martha, 1920-1950; undated; 10 folders (Box 36)
  - Rittenhouse, Jessie Belle (Box 36)
  - Ritter, Margaret Tod (Box 36)
  - Roberts, Mary Eleanor (Box 36)
  - Robinson, Edwin Arlington (Box 36)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton (Box 36)
  - Roe, Robert J. (Box 36)
  - Roerich Museum (Box 36)
  - Rolvaag, O. E. (Box 36)
  - Rosenberg, Solomon (Box 36)
  - Ryan, Kathryn White (Box 36)
  - S, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Sarett, Lew (Box 37)
  - Sargent, Mary (Box 37)
  - The Saturday Review (Box 37)
  - Saul, George Brandon (Box 37)
  - Schauffler, Robert Haven (Box 37)
  - Schelling, Felix Emanuel (Box 37)
  - Seiffert, Marjorie Allen (Box 37)
  - Shaw, Bernard (Box 37)
  - Sinclair, Upton (Box 37)
  - Sinkler, Caroline (Box 37)
  - Skinner, Constance Lindsay (Box 37)
  - Skinner, Otis and Maud (Box 37)
  - The Smart Set (Box 37)
  - Smith, Alice Ravenel Huger (Box 37)
  - Smith, Chard Powers (Box 37)
  - Smith, May Riley (Box 37)
  - Spencer, Lilian White (Box 37)
  - Speyer, Leonora (Box 37)
  - Spiers, Alexander Guy Holbern (Box 37)
  - Stillman, Mildred Whitney (Box 37)
  - Stokowski, Leopold (Box 37)
  - Storey, Violet Allyn (Box 37)
  - Stork, Theophilus Baker, 1906-1932; undated; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Summers, Elizabeth Montgomery (Box 38)
  - Summers, Hazel Thane, 1918-1932; undated; 3 folders (Box 38)
  - T (Box 38)
  - Taylor, Elkanah East (Box 38)
  - Teasdale, Sara (Box 38)
  - Thayer, Georgiana (Box 38)
  - Thayer, Mary Dixon (Box 38)
  - Thayer, William R. (Box 38)
  - Towles, Alice Otis Bird, See Bird, Stephen Moylan (Box 38)
  - Tumbull, Margaret (Box 38)
  - Turner, Lillian Elizabeth (Box 38)
  - U (Box 38)
  - Untermeyer, Louis (Box 38)
  - V (Box 38)
  - Van Slyke, Berenice (Box 38)
  - Victor, Josephine (Box 38)
  - Viereck, George Sylvester (Box 38)
  - Vinal, Harold (Box 38)
  - The Virginia Quarterly Review (Box 38)
  - W, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Wachtmeister, Axel Raoul (Box 39)
  - Wagenar, Bernard (Box 39)
  - Wallace, Emma Gray (Box 39)
  - Washburn, Oliver M. (Box 39)
  - Washington, H. Wyatt (Box 39)
  - Wattles, Willard Austin (Box 39)
  - Weil, James L. (Box 39)
  - Welch, Catharine (Box 39)
  - Welles, Winifred (Box 39)
  - Wheelock, John Hall (Box 39)
  - Whibley, Leonard (Box 39)
  - White, Barbara Ackerman, See Ackerman, Barbara (Box 39)
  - Whiteside, Mary Brent (Box 39)
  - Widdemer, Margaret (Box 39)
  - Wilkinson, Marguerite Ogden Bigelow (Box 39)
  - Williams, Oscar (Box 39)
  - Wilson, John French (Box 39)
  - Wister, Margaret (Box 39)
  - Wister, Owen (Box 39)
  - Wood, Clement (Box 39)
  - Wrinn, Mary J. J. (Box 39)
  - The Yale Review (Box 39)
  - Yeats, William Butler (Box 39)
  - Young, Ruth Comfort Mitchell (Box 39)
  - Z (Box 39)
  - Yale University Press (Box 39)